Guide to the Rudyard Kipling collection, 1881-1960
Kipling, Rudyard collection, 1881-1960
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Rudyard Kipling collection, 1881-1960 (bulk 1890-1920)
4610
Rudyard Kipling, 1865-1936.
4.2 linear ft.
Manuscripts, letters, clippings, photographs, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, letters, clippings, and photographs by, to, or relating to Rudyard Kipling.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Rudyard Kipling was an English author and journalist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts, letters, clippings, and photographs by, to, or relating to Rudyard Kipling. Included are autograph and typewritten manuscripts of poems and stories by Kipling, with his autograph corrections; 258 letters written by Kipling, ranging in date from 1886-1935; letters by others to or about Kipling; and numerous newspaper and magazine clippings and photographs, including newspaper articles by or about Kipling, obituaries of him, and reviews of and publishers' advertisements for his books. Also included are a questionnaire Kipling filled out in 1881 concerning his favorite authors and his views on literature and life; typewritten memoirs about Kipling by his friend Edmonia Taylor Hill; a diary kept by Mrs. Hill from 1888-1890, including material about Kipling; 10 chapters of a typewritten manuscript biography of Kipling by Betty Miller; 50 photographs taken by Prof. Hill to accompany the text of Kipling's book From Sea to Sea; and an album of photographs of India dating from 1888.
Kipling's letters include comments and instructions concerning the publication of his books and stories; contemporary political developments in England and in British foreign affairs, especially the question of home rule for India; and a few requests for research materials which he used in writing his novel Captains Courageous. Correspondents include John Frederick Bridge, George Sydenham Clarke, Sir Henry Craik, Monsieur Garnier, Macmickan, General Sterling, Edward Lucas White, and Leonard Raven-Hill. Also included are transcripts of 61 letters written by Charles J. Paterson, many of them to Edmonia Taylor Hill.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936.; Bridge, Frederick, 1844-1924.; Clarke, George Sydenham, 1848-; Craik, Henry, 1846-1927.; Hill, Edmonia Taylor.; Miller, Betty.; Paterson, Charles J.; Raven-Hill, L. (Leonard), 1867-1942.; White, Edward Lucas, 1866-1934.
Subjects:
English literature--19th century.; English literature--20th century.; Authors and publishers--England.; Press and politics--England.; Authorship.; Women--Diaries.; Authors, English.
Places:
Great Britain--Politics and government--1901-1936.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--1901-1936.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--India.; India--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; India--Description and travel.; India--Politics and government--1919-1947.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Portraits.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Collection #13-6-1232 is restricted.
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection #13-6-1232.
Book collection also held in the repository, including many first English and first American editions of Kipling's works and copies signed by him.
CONTAINER LIST
- Manuscripts (Box 1)
- Outgoing correspondence
  - 1886-1898 (Box 2)
  - 1899-1922 (Box 3)
  - 1923-1935, undated (Box 4)
- Incoming correspondence and manuscripts
  - A-Mr (Box 5)
  - Ms-Z (Box 6)
- Kiplingiana (Box 7)
- Bound Manuscripts
  - "Captains Courageous" notebook, 1
  - Transcripts of Kipling letters, 1896-1929; 2, 3+
  - "Kipling: The End" scrapbook, 1893-1937; 4+
  - Letter to Lady Dufferin, November 9, 1892; 5
  - Letter to R.I. Harding, October 10, 1897; 6 tiny
  - Letter to Dr. Hale, January 15, 1895; 7
  - Photograph album on India, 1886?; 8+
  - Kipling memoir by Edmonia Hill (draft), 9++
  - Fiction and criticism scrapbooks, circa 1890-1928; 10-14
  - Kiplingiana, circa 1891-1954 (bulk 1891-1924)
    - Kiplingiana, 15+
    - Kiplingiana, 16++
    - Kiplingiana, 17
    - Kiplingiana, 18++-20++
  - Kipling memoir by Edmonia Hill (2 fair copies), 21+, 22+
  - Signed verse from "In the Neolithic Age", 23
  - Kipling cuttings, circa 1891-1933
    - Kipling cuttings, 24-28
    - Kipling cuttings, 29+- 31+
    - Kipling cuttings, 32++
    - Kipling cuttings, 33+
    - Kipling cuttings, 35++
    - Kipling cuttings, 36+
    - Kipling cuttings, 37++
    - Kipling cuttings, 38+ (index)
  - Putnam, (printing specimen by Kipling), 1900; 41 tiny
  - Letter to Howard Pyle, August 25, 1894; 42
  - Kipling stories in American and illustrated magazines, 1895-1920; 43
  - Katy Anne Eaton, Rudyard Kipling miscellany, 44+
  - Photographs for From Sea to Sea (copies), 45 tiny
  - Letters to Lord Sydenham, May 5, 1918 - September 13, 1930; 46
  - Verse from "A Tree Song" with leaves and Kipling portrait, 47++
  - John Lockwood Kipling and Alice Kipling notebooks, 1889-1931; 48 2 vols.